Welcome to the Jupyter Lab for day four.
주피터 연구소의 4일째 날이죠
It's going to look very familiar because it's actually I've started with a duplicate of day three.
아주 익숙해 보일 거예요 왜냐하면 사실 3일째의 복제로 시작했거든요
And in this duplicate there's a few cells.
이 복제본에는 셀이 몇 개 있어요
We're going to want to rerun the imports at the beginning connecting our environment.
환경을 연결하는 시작에서 가져오기를 다시 실행해야죠
We're going to want to connect to our frontier models.
개척 시대 모델과 교감하고 싶어요
Because guess what.
왜인 줄 알아요?
We're going to be able to get the frontier models to work side by side with open source models, which
개척 모델들을 오픈 소스 모델과 나란히 작동시킬 수 있게 될 겁니다 아주 근사하겠죠 get the
is going to be terrific.
new-file
Uh, we'll get our prompts, our messages function, if you remember that something that can write to
프롬프트, 메시지 함수도 있습니다. C++ 파일을 OUTPUT하여 쓸 수 있는 것을
output C plus plus file.
기억하신다면요.
Um, this I don't think we need to run because it's going to be overwritten.
이건 중복 기재될 테니 실행할 필요 없을 것 같아요
But then our code for our Pi program, we don't need to try it out because you'll remember that.
파이 프로그램 코드는 외우실 테니 안 해 봐도 돼요
But we will get our code for the hard program that looks for subarrays of arrays with the largest cumulative
근데 가장 누적된 수에 대한 배열을 찾는 하드 프로그램을 위한 코드를 얻게 될 거예요
Um, and we do need this stream, GPT function.
스트림과 GPT 함수도 필요해요
And we need this stream, Claude function.
이 개울이 필요해요 클로드 함수요
And we need this optimize function, although we're about to overwrite it.
덮어쓰기 직전이지만 최적화 함수가 필요해요
And you'll remember the gorgeous gradient functions will take execute Python and execute C plus plus,
이 멋진 그러데이션 함수는 파이썬 을 실행하고 C++를 실행합니다 다른
which, uh, I hope you remember that this is something which is not to be shared with others.
이들과 공유하지 않는다는 걸 기억하시길 바라요
You don't want to allow people to have the ability to execute arbitrary Python and C plus plus code
파이썬 + C+ 코드를 임의로 실행할 수 있도록 허용해서는
on your box.
안 되죠
That's not a good idea.
좋은 생각이 아니에요
So keep the Gradio interface to yourself and don't say share equals true for that.
그러니 그래디오 인터페이스는 혼자만 알고 공유 = true라고 하지 마세요
And then some CSS to make it look fancy.
CSS 덕분에 근사해 보이죠
All right.
좋아요
And now we get to our new code.
Get in get 새로운 코드예요
And it is going to be extremely simple.
아주 간단한 거예요
We start with some imports.
수입품부터 시작하죠
We're importing from Huggingface hub, the login function you've seen before, but also a class called
휴깅페이스 허브에서 불러오고 있어요 로그인 함수죠 인퍼런스 클라이언트라는
inference client.
클래스이기도 해요
And we're importing the the tokenizer.
토큰라이저를 불러올 거예요
We're going to log in to hugging face.
얼굴 포옹에 로그인할게요
There we go.
됐어요
And now just some constants.
이제 변함없는 것들만 남았어요
Code is this is the name of the code model I've also got here code Gemma in case you want to give it
코드 모델의 이름이죠 여기 code젬마도 있어요 시도해보시고 저보다
a try and see if you have more success than me.
성공했는지 보시라고요
This is the URL of my endpoint, so it's just taken from my endpoint page.
이건 제 엔드포인트 URL이에요 제 엔드포인트 페이지에서 가져온 거죠
I can just take this this URL.
이 URL을 가져갈게요
That is where my endpoint is running right now and costing me $0.80 an hour.
지금 제 엔드포인트가 실행되는 곳이죠 0달러가 들었어요 시간당 80달러요
And this is code Gemma that is sadly paused as it was not particularly stable.
이건 코드 젬마인데 안타깝게도 일시 중단됐어요 안정적이지 않아서요
Okay, so let's give this a try.
좋아요, 그럼 해 보죠
So remember tokenizer you can create using the auto tokenizer class and say Frompretrained pass in the
토큰마이저 기억하세요 오토 토큰마이저 클래스로 뭔가를 만들고 모델의 이름을 학습된 패스라고
name of your model and you will get the right tokenizer for that model.
하면 해당 모델에 맞는 토큰마이저를 얻게 돼요
And then I'm going to create this.
이제 이걸 만들게요
This is the function that we wrote before that's going to create the nice structured, um list of dictionaries
이건 우리가 전에 쓴 함수인데 구조화된 사전 목록을 만들어 파이가
to ask for the simple function for pi to be rewritten in C plus plus.
C++로 다시 쓰이는 간단한 함수를 요청할 거예요
And then we're going to use the Tokenizers apply chat template to turn that into text.
그런 다음 토큰라이저를 이용해 채팅 템플릿을 적용해 텍스트로 바꿀 거예요
Let's just take a look at what I'm talking about here.
제가 무슨 말을 하는지 한번 보죠
So if we remember to run that and then run this.
저걸 실행하고 이걸 실행하는 걸 기억한다면요
So first of all remember what messages is.
먼저 메시지가 뭔지 기억하세요
Messages is a list with two elements.
메시지란 두 가지 요소로 된 목록이에요
One of them has a system role.
그중 하나는 시스템 역할이에요
And that's the content.
그게 내용이에요
You were insistent that re-implements Python code blah blah blah.
파이썬 + 코드 어쩌고저쩌고를 다시 구현하라고 했죠
And then user uh, and then the user method.
그리고 사용자 메서드가 있죠
Now I should mention here just to in the spirit of being completely open, that I've added in a little
완전히 열려 있다는 의미에서 여기서 언급해야 할 게 있어요 약간의 힌트를 추가했어요
hint here, keep implementations of random number generators identical so that match, uh, results
난수 발생기의 구현을 동일하게 유지하세요 그래야 결과가 정확히 일치하니까요
Uh, so as you can imagine, uh, I've had to add hints here and there just to keep things on track.
짐작하시겠지만 진행을 유지하기 위해 여기저기 힌트를 추가해야 했어요
And you will see the results of that in a moment.
그 결과는 잠시 후에 보실 수 있어요
So this is, of course, the messages that you're familiar with.
이게 여러분이 익숙한 메시지예요
And now, if I show you what what text became after we applied the chat template, this if I print it,
이제 채팅 템플릿을 적용한 후 텍스트가 어떻게 됐는지 보여드릴게요 이걸 프린트하면 간격이 좀 더 길어질
it will be spaced out a bit better.
거예요 비트 템플릿
Let's see it printed.
인쇄해 봐요
Here we go.
시작할게요
Have a look at this.
이걸 보세요
So there is a special token I am start and then system and then the system message.
특별한 토큰이 있어요 시작할게요, 다음은 시스템 그다음은 시스템 메시지죠
And then the same thing with user.
사용자에게도 같은 거죠
And then this is the code.
이게 코드예요
And then it ends with this little prompt.
이 프롬프트로 끝나죠
That means that the LM is just going to keep going and give the assistance response.
달 착륙선은 계속 가서 지원 응답을 할 거예요
So with that now you would imagine that making the call to a hugging face endpoint, making this kind
이제 여러분은 포옹하는 얼굴 엔드포인트에 전화를 걸고 오픈 소스 모델에 이런 종류의 메시지를
of message to an open source model and getting back the response might be really difficult.
만들고 응답을 받는 게 아주 어려울 거라고 생각하겠죠
And it's not.
그렇지 않아요
It's one of those things that's just a couple of lines of code.
코드 두어 줄이면 되는 그런 것 중 하나죠
Here it is.
여기 있네요
It's as simple as this.
아주 간단해요
Uh, you create an object, the inference client and you tell it the URL of your endpoint and your hugging
객체를 생성합니다 inference 클라이언트요 그리고 엔드포인트 URL과 포옹하는 얼굴
face token, and then you just say client dot text generation.
토큰을 알려줍니다 그런 다음 클라이언트 .text 생성이라고 하죠
You pass in your text, you say, in this case I want to stream back results.
메시지를 전달하는 거죠 이 경우엔 결과를 스트리밍하고 싶어요
If you didn't have that, this would be even even shorter.
그게 없으면 더 짧아져요
But it's nice to see the results streaming back.
하지만 결과가 다시 흘러오는 걸 보니 좋네요
Um, and then max new tokens, um, is where you tell it that it can keep going for a little while.
최대 새 토큰은 한동안 계속될 수 있다고 알려주는 거예요
Uh, and let's see what happens.
어떻게 되는지 보죠
We're getting streaming back from my endpoint, running in hugging face, the result of the, uh, of
제 엔드포인트에서 스트리밍을 하고 있습니다 얼굴을 안으며 달리고 있습니다
of this conversion.
이 변환의 결과죠
Now, one thing I will point out while it's doing this, hopefully you're recognizing this code and
이 작업을 하는 동안 한 가지 지적하고 싶은 것은 여러분이 이 코드를
seeing that it's that it looks very legit, very solid conversion of py, uh, code from Python into
인식하고 계시길 바랍니다 아주 합법적으로 보이죠 파이썬 코드를 C+로 아주 탄탄하게 변환했어요
C plus.
비트는 처음에 C 플러스 플러스 코드를 설명하고
a bit of an explanation.
있어요
And it's also ending with a bunch of text about why it did what it did.
왜 그렇게 했는지에 대한 문자로 끝나기도 하고요
And this is despite the fact that my system message insists that it shouldn't do that.
내 시스템 메시지는 그러면 안 된다고 주장하는데도요
Um, it says, uh, do not provide any explanation, but I was not able, through the system message
어떤 설명도 하지 말라고 돼 있는데 시스템 메시지를 통해 설명을 하지 말라는 메시지를
to get it not to provide an explanation.
받을 수 없었어요 get it
Although, as you remember, GPT four and Claude do obey the instructions.
기억하시겠지만 GPT 4와 클로드는 지시를 잘 따르죠
So that's something I imagine you could spend more time working on that prompt to really try and make
프롬프트에서 시간을 더 들여 작업하면 그런 일이 일어나지 않도록 할 수
sure that it doesn't happen.
있을 것 같아요
But failing that, of course, it's very easy to do some post-processing and strip out the everything
하지만 그게 실패하면 post processing을
that comes up till the, uh, the start of the C plus plus code and up until the, um, so you could
해서 C 플러스 플러스 코드 시작까지 모든 걸 제거하는 게 아주 쉽죠 이 기호까지
strip out everything up until this symbol here and take what comes between that and here.
모든 걸 제거하고 이와 이 사이에 있는 걸 취할 수 있어요
So it'd be pretty easy to do that with some post-processing.
post processing을 하면 쉽게 할 수 있어요.
All right.
좋아요
Anyway, we've seen how easy it is to run inference.
추론을 실행하는 게 얼마나 쉬운지 보셨죠
Uh, I will see you next time when we will put this together in a UI and give it a whirl.
UI 상에서 함께 조립하고 실행할 때 다시 뵙죠. TMI TMI UI
See you then.
그때 봐요